Vincent Portier

Front-end software developer



https://vportier.com https://github.com/vincentportier

About me

Motivated junior software developer seeking a full-time opportunity to leverage my Javascript and React knowledge. I am a problem solver with a passion for learning new skills and a desire to adopt the best practices of a professional team. After 7 years as an accomplished Event Manager, I developped excellent project management skills and am now seeking to transition my career to the Tech Industry.

Projects

Liffre-Piela

I created a website for a French Charity. I've used Gatsby paired with Netlify CMS for a performant, easy to use and free solution. Netlify CMS produces Markdown files that are being queried with Graphql in Gatsby to generate the pages, routes and articles. The website has a perfect score in Lightouse in the speed, accessiblity, best practices and SEO categories Technologies: React, Gatsby, Netlify CMS, Netlify, Styled-Components, HTML, CSS, Hooks

vportier.com

My personal website built with React, Gatsby and Netlify. The content is updated by adding markdown files that are being queried in Gatsby with Graphql.

Technologies: React, Gatsby, Netlify, Styled-Components, HTML, CSS, Hooks and Context

Toudo

Toudo is an app that allows you to create tasks, schedule, prioritise, sort, file and comment on them. Toudo manages authentication and saves your tasks in Firebase. Toudo uses custom hooks to make API calls and set the context of the app with your tasks and projects. Technologies: React, HTML, CSS, Firebase, React Router, Hooks and Context

The Resistance: Avalon game

This web app is an adaptation of the game Avalon mainly built with React Technologies: React, HTML, CSS, React Router

Professional Experience

Senior Event Manager @ AusBiotech

Jun 2016 - Apr 2020 // Melbourne, Australia

Fully managed logistics, operations and sponsorship sales of two major international conferences generating over \$1 million profit

- ▶ Proposed and managed the transfer of 5 websites to a new CMS
- ▶ Redesigned and maintened the content of websites using HTML and CSS
- ▶ Managed our online registration system using an Event Management Platform and created dashboards to track and monitor our performance
- ▶ Worked closely with a provider to build and implement a Business Matching solution that led to 4000 facilitated meetings
- ▶ Communicated and collaborated with multi-disciplinary teams of providers, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis
- ▶ Designed weekly marketing email campaigns in HTML

Event & Communication Manager @ Ifaci

Apr 2013 - Jan 2016 // Paris, France

- ▶ Closely collaborated with a digital agency to design, develop and implement a custom registration platform for our International Conference (2000 delegates)
- ▶ Interfaced with designers and management team to develop, document, and manage the conference's marketing website
- ▶ Helped solidify a brand direction for our events to span across print and web

Event & Sponsorship coordinator @ Canal+

Aug 2010 - Aug 2011 // Paris, France

▶ Contributed extensively to the Sponsorship and PR strategy of the Winter X Games Europe

Skills

Programming languages JavaScript, HTML, CSS/Sass

Libraries & frameworks

React, Gatsby, Redux, Styled-Components, Moment.js, Material-UI

Tools & platforms

Git, Firebase, Netlify, Squarespace, Lightroom, Photoshop

Soft skills

Self-drive to learn, Project management, Teamwork, Customer service

Languages

French (native), English (fluent)

Currently learning

Node, Express MongoDB and Mongoose

Education

FreeCodeCamp Curriculum 2020 // Online

I completed 3 certifications:

- ▶ Responsive Web Design
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures
- Front End Libraries

Grenoble EM

2008-2012 // Grenoble, France

Master's degree in Management Volunteered in the school's Students Union for 2 years

University of Alberta

2012 // Edmonton, Canada Studied one term as an exchange student in the MBA program of the School of Business

Interests

Photography, Boardgames, Reading